hey everyone thanks for listening to The
Grow Your Life podcast my name is
Jeremiah Kowski I'm excited this is our
last podcast Before Christmas then we
head into the new year this is going to
be great I want to talk about how to
stay motivated especially as we go into
the new year and going through the
holiday how do you keep that motivation
going for you so one of those things a
lot of people ask is how do we do that
in fact I guess this podcast went live
on Christmas Eve so there we go well to
stay
motivated motivation is fleeting that's
one of the things is you have to really
ask yourself why am I doing this why am
I actually building my business what is
my reason for doing so it needs to be
bigger than you it needs to be bigger
than just oh I need to make some money
oh I want to have impact it needs to be
about a vision of where you're going and
so here's what is going to help you
number one get a vision for the life
that you want to live what is that life
that you want to have from your business
a lot of people are burning themselves
out to kind of create the kind of money
that they want to make and they are not
living the life that they want to live
that's designed the way that they want
they're just going through the motions
and and then they wonder why they're
struggling in their business I meet a
lot of people that they're not making
the kind of money they want to make and
they can't stay motivated to do the work
in their business so you got to have
that vision for the life that you are
creating above all else because what's
going to happen is when you start to
believe that thing is going to start to
happen for you when you start to get a
vision for the life that you're creating
those things start to happen for you I'm
going to tell you this you need to start
declaring you need to start speaking
into existence and you need to start
saying and affirming this amazing
beautiful thing wonderful thing is going
to start happening to me uh even if you
don't have evidence of it in your life
in 3D reality and that's one of the
things that I'll tell you for myself for
the longest time I used to go based off
of just what I could see in front of me
and my motivation would be up and down
up and down now I'll tell you you is
that I get a vision for what I'm
creating I get a vision for what's
happening and I believe that it's going
to happen now I've been in this industry
long enough that I can tell you that
this works I've been in this long enough
that the people who can truly see it
coming to pass before it actually
happens and they hold on to that Vision
they're the ones that are successful and
then what you do is you take
self-discipline combined with a vision
that's what motivation is is the
motivation comes when we discipline
ourselves to do the things that we know
that we need to do you know recording
this podcast every single week we got a
lot of episodes of this I don't feel
motivated most weeks to make the podcast
but what I do is I get a vision for the
impact I get a vision for the message
that I'm going to be talking about and
then I start recording and I get excited
about it and now the motivation starts
coming when when I actually start taking
action so here's what happens when it
comes to motivation the science behind
it is that if you start doing the work
you start doing the stuff that you've
been putting off the motivation will
start to come in after you do those
things now here's another thing that can
help you with that motivation is not
just doing the work but also taking care
of yourself getting enough sleep eating
well um you know I take number of
different supplements I work out I eat
really well and and I tell you we got
two we have brand newborn baby so sleep
is a little bit of a thing that we're
that's like I fight for to get my sleep
um but it makes a difference and for you
number one take care of yourself take
care of your health take care of your
physical body and then number
two is see in your mind what is that
life that I'm creating write it down
make it tangible put it on a piece of
paper what is the house that you want to
live in
what is the kind type of bank account
that you want to have what's that credit
score that you want to have what is the
impact that you're going to have who are
the people that you're going to be
helping and by the way I'm preaching to
myself here when I say this because I
still have to remind myself of this I
have a dream and a vision for the types
of clients that I want to help thousands
of people that I want to help them
become Millionaires and sometimes it
becomes demotivating when I start to see
people not applying the things that I'm
teaching
and then I say okay well what can I do
to help be a better leader to people how
can I help lead people better and I come
and I look at it from a perspective of
what can I do to grow in that skill set
so another thing that you can do that
can help you with your motivation is
when we grow in a skill set we start to
believe that it's going to happen for us
sometimes the reason why we lack
motivation is we lack skill and we don't
know what we're doing that's why getting
mentorship that's why in my coaching
program the client growth accelerator I
mentor people every single week on how
to get results get more clients get more
leads in their business and turn things
into the positive successful Financial
results that they want and so if you're
somebody that you're you're going out
there you got a you got a vision for
your
business you got to do the work and you
got to show up and you got to do the
hard things and the hard things
sometimes it's not sexy sometimes it's
not exciting sometimes it's not what you
want to do today but it's worth it and
it's
worth continuing to show up staying
consistent and doing the work motivation
is fleeting consistency and
self-discipline will keep you motivated
now I will say this don't just keep
doing the same thing over and over again
and expecting to get a different result
that's definition of insanity we don't
want to do that we want to say okay this
didn't work okay what can I learn from
this what can I apply what can I do
differently and that's going to shift
things for you as well when you can
learn how to do things a little bit
differently when you can learn how to
apply them just subtly differently in
your in your life in your business it
will produce those different results for
you okay so again this is a real simple
pep talk it's not a long drawn out
podcast episode but I'll tell you that
these are some of the things that I've
learned that have helped me and then
another one is is that take a look at
who are the friends that you're spending
time with are you spending time around
people that are demotivating you that
are that are making you feel doubtful
that you can do it they don't believe
that you can do it they're starting to
speak against the stuff that you're
creating maybe it's your family all this
factors come into play are you are you
watching news media are you scrolling
social media what is influencing your
brain space we got to take account for
those things if we're lacking motivation
we got to take account for those things
now here's another thing too when it
comes to motivation a little bit of the
science behind this and this is
something I think that will help you is
sometimes we become addicted to very
high dopamine activities things that
trigger High dopamine in us and so when
it feels like we're not getting the
results that we want it's not triggering
that dopamine inside of us that makes us
feel like it's getting a payoff and so
then we end up feeling like we're doing
the wrong thing because we haven't
trained our brain that sometimes and
this is one of the biggest things in
business you're not going to get those
big dopamine payoffs while you do the
work and you might not even get it when
you take action it you might not get the
results right away but you got to learn
to stay disciplined even though you're
not getting those triggers those things
that give you that high that happens
like a slot machine I think a lot of us
we have this sort of like a gambling
slot machine approach to our business
and then if if we get all sevens then
everything's great but the truth is
we're not going to get that all the time
and you got to keep playing the game and
you got to realize that it's not always
going to work out but that's why you got
to stay say okay I'm not going to quit
I'm going to continue and I'm going to
keep moving forward and when we can
learn as well to kind of reset our brain
around dopamine one of the best ways we
can do that again is not spend a lot of
time scrolling social media um one of
the things that you can do is again if
we ground ourselves if we take some time
away from media and things like that
it'll actually reset those different
receptors in our brain
to where we then end up
um getting that payoff from doing the
work and here's the thing so instead of
expecting the big dopamine payoff from
the results from your work shift it to
where you actually feel that dopamine
payoff from doing the work and you start
hacking the dopamine receptors in your
brain to where doing the work itself
creates the reward center in your brain
you start feeling the reward of doing
the work versus the reward of the big
payoff and the big outcome and that will
actually hack your brain science in a
big way it really will to where you
start to congratulate yourself just for
showing up and doing the work and that
will help actually motivate you because
then you become motivated to get the
payoff from doing the work all right so
all of these things combined these can
help you and I hope that they will help
you I'd love to see you in my client
growth accelerator program where I can
help hold you accountable and help you
get the results that you want in your
business grow your life everybody we'll
talk soon have a good
[Applause]
[Music]